Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection, circa 1930-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Photographs of Yvar Mikhashoff with other people, other people without Mikhashoff, Mikhashoff alone when part of a photographic sequence, and scenes from Mikhashoff's travels, circa 1930-circa 1990, II.; Containers 3-4, 285 photographs
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing in front of piano at Schiller College (location not specified), March 8 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-151)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing in front of piano at Schiller College (location not specified), March 8 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-152)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff walking through foyer at Schiller College (location not specified), March 8 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-153)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing in concert hall at Schiller College (location not specified), March 8 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-154)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff seated at piano at Schiller College (location not specified), March 8 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-155)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing at piano at Schiller College (location not specified), March 8 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-156)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff iin green sweater performing at piano, November 1980, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-157)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff iin green sweater performing at piano, side view, November 1980, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-158)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket performing at piano, November 1980, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-159)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket performing at piano, November 1980, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-160)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket speaking into microphone while seated at piano, November 1980, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-161)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket speaking into microphone while seated at piano, November 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-162)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket performing at piano, November 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-163)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing on violoncello of Frances-Marie Uitti, William Kirkpatrick partially in frame, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 3, Item YM03-164)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Frances-Marie Uitti, and William Kirkpatrick performing John Cage's Theatre Piece, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 3, Item YM03-165)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Frances-Marie Uitti, and William Kirkpatrick performing John Cage's Theatre Piece, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 3, Item YM03-166)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Frances-Marie Uitti, and William Kirkpatrick performing John Cage's Theatre Piece, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 3, Item YM03-167)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Frances-Marie Uitti, and William Kirkpatrick performing John Cage's Theatre Piece, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 3, Item YM03-168)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Frances-Marie Uitti, and William Kirkpatrick performing John Cage's Theatre Piece, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 3, Item YM03-169)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frances-Marie Uitti, violoncello, taking a bow, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-170)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frances-Marie Uitti, violoncello, taking a bow, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-171)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aaron Copland, March 1981, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-172)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Aaron Copland, and Emil Mackay, Mikhashoff's father, March 1981, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-173)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Aaron Copland, and unidentified male, March 1981, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-174)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and his father, Emil Mackay, March 1981, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-175)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and unidentified male, March 1981, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-176)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing in front of a replica of the Statue of Liberty, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-177)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing in front of a replica of the Statue of Liberty, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-178)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff blowing out candles on birthday cake with unidentified male, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-179)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff dancing with unidentified female, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 3, Item YM03-180)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Elliott Carter, Michael McCandless (barely visible), and Henry Brant, 1982, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-001)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Elliott Carter, Michael McCandless, and Henry Brant, 1982, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-002)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Elliott Carter, Michael McCandless, and Henry Brant, 1982, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-003)
  - Henry Brant in visor, undated, 1 black and white photograph; McGowan, Ann (Box 4, Item YM04-004)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Henry Brant, and friends at outdoor café (3 snapshots conjoined), undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-005)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-006)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress with unidentified male, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-007)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress with two unidentified males and unidentified female, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-008)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress with Frances-Marie Uitti and unidentified male, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-009)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress with Frances-Marie Uitti and unidentified woman, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-010)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with Danish composers, Ib Nørholm, Per Nørgaard, and Poul Ruders, 1983, 1 black and white photograph; Hauerbach, R. (Box 4, Item YM04-011)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with composer Ib Nørholm standing behind him; Poul Ruders in right hand upper corner by door frame with open score in hands, 1983, 1 black and white photograph; Hauerbach, R. (Box 4, Item YM04-012)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in red jacket and white scarf, with Michael McCandless and two unidentified people outside Chi-Chi's restaurant, 1983, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-013)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frances-Marie Uitti standing outside, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-014)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff (left) at table with three unidentified people, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-015)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in blue jacket and red tie with four unidentified people, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-016)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with Lejaren Hiller and Frances-Marie Uitti, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-017)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with Conlon Nancarrow and unidentified male in Nancarrow's studio in Mexico, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-018)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with Conlon Nancarrow, Mrs. Nancarrow (Yoko Sugiura Yamamoto), and unidentified male, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-019)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Conlon Nancarrow, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-020)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Conlon Nancarrow, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-021)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Conlon Nancarrow, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-022)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Conlon Nancarrow, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-023)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Conlon Nancarrow examining a piano roll, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-024)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket, Nils Vigeland, Christian Eggen, and Erik Bye, 1984, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-025)
  - Contact sheet with images of Yvar Mikhashoff, Nils Vigeland, Christian Eggen, and Erik Bye, 1984, 1 black and white contact sheet; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-026)
  - Contact sheet with images of Yvar Mikhashoff, Nils Vigeland, Christian Eggen, and Erik Bye, 1984, 1 black and white contact sheet; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-027)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, in his teens or early twenties, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-028)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket taking bow at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-029)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket taking bow at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-030)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano with three unidentified males at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-031)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt walking through Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-032)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano with unidentified page turner at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-033)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano with three unidentified males at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-034)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano with unidentified page turner at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-035)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano with unidentified page turner at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-036)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket taking bow at Almeida Theatre, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-037)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with unidentified male, 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-038)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Henri Dutilleux, and Oliver Knussen at Aldeburgh Festival, June 1985, 1 color photograph; Luckhurst, Nigel (Box 4, Item YM04-039)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Anthony De Mare outside Baird Hall, University at Buffalo, August 1985, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-040)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and two unidentified females, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-041)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and two unidentified males, all with champagne glasses, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-042)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in tan sweater at piano with unidentified male, 1985-10, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-043)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in tan sweater with unidentified male, 1985-10, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-044)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in tan sweater at piano with Frances-Marie Uitti, 1985-10, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-045)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frances-Marie Uitti mugging for the camera, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-046)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and his cousin Davia, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-047)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and his cousin Davia, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-048)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and John Cage, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-049)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, John Cage, and Isabelle Ganz, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-050)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Frederic Rzewski, and Pierre Audi at Almeida Theatre, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-051)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frederic Rzewski in conversation at Almeida Theatre, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-052)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frederic Rzewski in conversation at Almeida Theatre, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-053)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frederic Rzewski in conversation at Almeida Theatre, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-054)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frederic Rzewski in conversation at Almeida Theatre, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-055)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Frederic Rzewski in performance at two pianos at Almeida Theatre, with page-turners Francoise Walot and Bob Briggs (next to Mikhashoff), June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-056)
  - David Felder, composer, outside Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Loonan, Tom (Box 4, Item YM04-057)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and David Felder outside Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Loonan, Tom (Box 4, Item YM04-058)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Pierre-Yves Artuad, flute, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-059)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Pierre-Yves Artaud, flute, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-060)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Pierre-Yves Artaud, flute, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-061)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Pierre-Yves Artaud, flute, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-062)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Sylvano Bussotti in conversation at Almeida Theatre, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-063)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in foreground, Halina Moretti at dressing table, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-064)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with Halina Moretti, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-065)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano (background) with Halina Moretti, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-066)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with Halina Moretti on floor, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-067)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with Halina Moretti leaning on piano, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-068)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with Halina Moretti leaning on piano, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-069)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with composer Luis De Pablo examining score, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-070)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at piano with composer Luis De Pablo examining score, unidentified male at left, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-071)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in conversation with Luis de Pablo at Almeida Theatre, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-072)
  - Giacinto Scelsi and Rohan de Saram, violoncellist, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-073)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and violoncellist Rohan de Saram shaking hands with composer Giacinto Scelsi, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-074)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection;, 1986, 1 photograph; Unidentified; (Box 4, Item YM04-075;)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-076)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-077)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-078)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-079)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-080)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-081)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-082)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Aki Takahashi performing at two pianos, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-083)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff, Toru Takemitsu, and Oliver Knussen, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-084)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing behind Toru Takemitsu, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-085)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and Toru Takemitsu performing at piano, 4 hands, June 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 4, Item YM04-086)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing at electric keyboard with ensemble, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-087)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing at piano with ensemble, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-088)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing at piano with unidentified page turner, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-089)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing at piano with unidentified page turner, 1986, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-090)
  - Virgil Thomson, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-091)
  - Virgil Thomson seated in his apartment, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-092)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing behind seated Virgil Thomson, with unidentified cameraman, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-093)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with unidentified Asian friends, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-094)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at dinner with unidentified Asian friends, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-095)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with unidentified Balinese male, August 1987, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-096)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with five unidentified males on stage, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-097)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff with unidentified violoncellist, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-098)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing at piano with unidentified string trio on stage, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-099)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing with unidentified male, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-100)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white suit beneath Fire Exit sign, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-101)
  - Contact sheet with images of Yvar Mikhashoff, John Boudler, Martha Herr, Thomas Halpin, and David Kuehn, undated, 1 black and white contact sheet; Blue Photo (Firm) (Box 4, Item YM04-102)
  - Contact sheet with images of Thomas Halpin, Yvar Mikhashoff, John Boudler, Martha Herr, and David Kuehn, undated, 1 black and white contact sheet; Blue Photo (Firm) (Box 4, Item YM04-103)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff performing on strings of piano, and John Cage, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 4, Item YM04-104)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff and John Cage sitting on stools, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 4, Item YM04-105)
- Duplicates (unnumbered) and negatives, circa 1930-1993, III.; Container 5
- Snapshots, circa 1960-1993, IV.; Container 6: approximately 350 snapshots, with and without negatives, in 42 photo envelopes.
  Most of the remaining photographs are of landscapes and scenes encountered during Mikhashoff's travels to Czechoslovokia, Egypt, Israel, Jordan, and Mexico.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Musicians--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Pianists--Photographs; Mikhashoff, Yvar--Photographs
Genres
Photographs
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Archive
The Yvar Mikhashoff Archive consists of the following separate components:
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Compositions
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Transcriptions
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Annotated Scores
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Tangos
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Sound Recordings
Yvar Mikhashoff Cassette Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Video Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Slide Collection